Guide to the Elizabeth Gedney Christensen Gardening Collection 1822-1994
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Elizabeth Gedney Christensen Gardening Collection
1882-1994
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Cage 667
Christensen, Elizabeth Gedney
18 containers. 19 linear feet of shelf space. 1200 items.
The collection consists chiefly of garden, nursery and seed catalogs, rounded out by miscellaneous garden magazines, pamphlets, brochures, similar materials. The earliest of the catalogs is dated 1866, while the most recent is from 1994. A few of the pamphlets are of even earlier years.
Elizabeth Christensen of Lompoc, California, collected older garden catalogs, and some related publications, over a period several years beginning in about 1970 and continuing until the transfer of the collection to the Washington State University Libraries in 1996. Catalogs were acquired from many sources, including individuals, antique dealers, and chance finds. Some catalogs, chiefly recent, were acquired from their publishers.
Mrs. Christensen has explained some aspects of the history of horticultural catalogs in a manuscript, Of Seed Catalogs and Companies that accompanies the collection. She adds further information in Japanese Imperial Morning Glories, Pacific Horticulture (Fall 1989).
The collection consists chiefly of garden, nursery and seed catalogs, rounded out by miscellaneous garden magazines, pamphlets, brochures, similar materials. The earliest of the catalogs is dated 1866, while the newest is from 1994. A few of the pamphlets are of even earlier years.
The materials are arranged in two alphabetical sequences, one of the catalogs and the rest of all other items. The catalogs are identified by the issuing firms, then placed in alphabetical order. A few large catalogs are arranged in an oversize sequence following the main alphabetical sequence. Most other items are identified by title or author, and arranged roughly alphabetically, with exceptions to accommodate variance of size and to fit items into the storage cartons.
This collection is open for research use.
The Christensen Gardening Collection was donated to the Washington State University Libraries in 1996 (MS96-10) and 1998 (MS98-07) by Mrs. Elizabeth Christensen of Lompoc, California, who also contributed funding for the processing of the collection.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Christensen, Elizabeth Gedney. --Archives
Gardening -- United States--History--Sources; Gardening -- Catalogs; Seed industry and trade--History--Sources; Seeds -- Catalogs; Vegetables -- Seeds--Catalogs; Nursery stock --Catalogs; Plants, Ornamental--Catalogs; Flowers -- Catalogs; Horticultural crops--Seeds--Catalogs; Gardening -- 19th century--Periodicals; Gardening -- 20th century--Periodicals
Agriculture
Japanese imperial morning glories Fall, 1989 Pacific horticulture; Garden magazine; Genessee farmer; Flower grower; Address delivered before the Philadelphia society for promoting agriculture 1822; Of seed catalogs and companies; Elizabeth Christensen Gedney gardening collection
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Garden Catalogs
  - Abbey Garden - Cacti and Succulents, 1980 (Box-folder 1 / 1)
  - Abundant Life, 1989; 1990; 1991; 1992 (Box-folder 1 / 2)
  - Ackerman Nurseries, 1952; 1955 (Box-folder 1 / 3)
  - Aggeler and Musser, 1920; 1949 (Box-folder 1 / 4)
  - Agrico, undated (Box-folder 1 / 5)
  - Alexander County Nurseries, 1923 (Box-folder 1 / 6)
  - Allen (W.F.) Co, 1947; 1949 (Box-folder 1 / 7)
  - Allen's Nurseries and Seed House, 1936; 1957 (Box-folder 1 / 8)
  - Alneer Brothers, 1894; 1902; 1905; 1906; 1908; 1911; 1914; 1941 (Box-folder 1 / 9)
  - American Field Seed Company, 1927 (Box-folder 1 / 10)
  - American Horticultural Society, 1978 (Box-folder 1 / 11)
  - American Mutual Seed Company, 1918; 1919 (Box-folder 1 / 12)
  - American Rose and Plant Company, 1929 (Box-folder 1 / 13)
  - American Seed and Plant Company, 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 14)
  - Ames Implement and Seed Company, 1917 (Box-folder 1 / 15)
  - Archia's Seed Store, 1913 (Box-folder 1 / 16)
  - Armstrong Nurseries, 1957; 1966; 1967; 1987 (Box-folder 1 / 17)
  - Baldwin (O.A.D.) Nurseries, 1954; 1955 (Box-folder 1 / 18)
  - Ball Seed, 1957; 1976; 1985; 1986 (Box-folder 1 / 19)
  - Barcelona servicio municipal de parques y jardines, Catalago de semillas, 1958 (Box-folder 1 / 19.1)
  - Barnes Bros. Nursery Co., 1947 (Box-folder 1 / 20)
  - Barrett (W.E.) Company, 1921 (Box-folder 1 / 21)
  - Bay State, 1929; 1947 (Box-folder 1 / 22)
  - Berger (H.H) and Co., 1913 (Box-folder 1 / 23)
  - Berry (A.A.) Seed Company, 1919; 1920; 1925-26; 1929; 1930; 1940 (Box-folder 1 / 24)
  - BioQuest International, 1987-88; 1989; 1990 (Box-folder 1 / 25)
  - Blanc (A.) and Company, 1890 (Box-folder 1 / 26)
  - Bliss (B.K.) and Sons, 1870 (Box-folder 1 / 27)
  - Bobbink and Atkins, 1904 (Box-folder 1 / 28)
  - Bodger Seeds Ltd., 1967; 1968; 1969; 1973; 1977; 1979; 1981; 1982; 1992; 1993 (Box-folder 1 / 29)
  - Bongarzone Brothers, undated (Box-folder 1 / 30)
  - Borbeleta Gardens,Inc., 1989-90; 1990 (Box-folder 1 / 31)
  - Bountiful Ridge Nurseries, 1946 (Box-folder 1 / 32)
  - Bradley Brothers, 1932 (Box-folder 1 / 33)
  - Brand's Peony Farms, 1928; 1951 (Box-folder 1 / 34)
  - Breck (Joseph) and Sons High Grade Seeds, 1907; 1914; 1956; 1961; 1979; 1981; 1982; 1987; 1988; 1989 (Box-folder 1 / 35)
  - Briggs and Brothers, 1873; 1876; 1888 (Box-folder 1 / 36)
  - Brower Seed and Supply Company, undated (Box-folder 1 / 37)
  - Brudy's Tropical Exotics, 1994 (Box-folder 1 / 38)
  - Brun's Seed Co., 1923 (Box-folder 1 / 39)
  - Buckbee (H.W.) Seed and Plant Guide, 1898; 1899; 1920; 1926; 1927; 1929; 1935 (Box-folder 1 / 40)
  - Buist (Robert) Company, 1918; 1931; 1932 (Box-folder 1 / 41)
  - Bunting's Nurseries,Inc., 1947 (Box-folder 1 / 42)
  - Burgess Seed and Nursery Book, 1922; 1931; 1932; 1939 1940; 1941 (Box-folder 2 / 43)
  - Burgess Seed and Nursery Book, 1947; 1954; 1958; 1961; 1969; 1977; 1978 (Box-folder 2 / 44)
  - Burpee (Benson, Burpee and Co.), Burpee (W. Atlee) and Co.; 1878; 1888; 1897; 1904; 1905, (Box-folder 2 / 45)
  - Burpee (W. Atlee) and Co., 1906; 1911; 1914; 1915 (Box-folder 2 / 46)
  - Burpee (W. Atlee) and Co., 1919; 1924; 1929; 1930; 1931 (Box-folder 2 / 47)
  - Burpee (W. Atlee) and Co., 1934; 1935; 1937 (Box-folder 2 / 48)
  - Burpee (W. Atlee) and Co., 1939 (Box-folder 2 / 49)
  - Burpee (W. Atlee) and Co., 1942; 1945; 1946; 1947 (Box-folder 2 / 50)
  - Burpee (W. Atlee) and Co., 1948 (Box-folder 2 / 51)
  - Burpee (W. Atlee) and Co., 1949 (Box-folder 2 / 52)
  - Burpee (W. Atlee) and Co., 1950; 1950, (Box-folder 2 / 53)
  - Burpee (W. Atlee) and Co., 1951 (Box-folder 2 / 54)
  - Burpee (W. Atlee) and Co., 1952 (Box-folder 2 / 55)
  - Burpee (W. Atlee) and Co., 1953 (Box-folder 3 / 56)
  - Burpee (W. Atlee) and Co., 1954 (Box-folder 3 / 57)
  - Burpee (W. Atlee) and Co., 1955 (Box-folder 3 / 58)
  - Burpee (W. Atlee) and Co., 1956 (Box-folder 3 / 59)
  - Burpee (W. Atlee) and Co., 1957 (Box-folder 3 / 60)
  - Burpee (W. Atlee) and Co., 1958 (Box-folder 3 / 61)
  - Burpee (W. Atlee) and Co., 1959 (Box-folder 3 / 62)
  - Burpee (W. Atlee) and Co., 1959 (Box-folder 3 / 63)
  - Burpee (W. Atlee) and Co., 1960 (Box-folder 3 / 64)
  - Burpee (W. Atlee) and Co., 1961 (Box-folder 3 / 65)
  - Burpee (W. Atlee) and Co., 1961 (Box-folder 3 / 66)
  - Burpee (W. Atlee) and Co., 1962; 1963 (Box-folder 4 / 67)
  - Burpee (W. Atlee) and Co., 1964; 1965; 1966 (Box-folder 4 / 68)
  - Burpee (W. Atlee) and Co., 1973; 1974; 1976; 1977 (Box-folder 4 / 69)
  - Burpee (W. Atlee) and Co., 1978; 1979 (Box-folder 4 / 70)
  - Burpee (W. Atlee) and Co., 1980; 1981; 1982; 1983 (Box-folder 4 / 71)
  - Burpee (W. Atlee) and Co., 1983 (Box-folder 4 / 72)
  - Burpee (W. Atlee) and Co., 1985; 1986; 1991 (Box-folder 4 / 73)
  - Burrell (D.V.) Seed Growers Co., 1944 (Box-folder 4 / 74)
  - Butchart Gardens, 1982 (Box-folder 4 / 75)
  - California Nursery Company, 1946 (Box-folder 4 / 76)
  - Call's Nurseries, 1947 (Box-folder 4 / 77)
  - Calla Greenhouses, (Templin and Sons), 1895; 1901 (Box-folder 4 / 78)
  - Carter's Tested Seeds, 1923 (Box-folder 4 / 79)
  - Cashman's Seeds, 1916 (Box-folder 4 / 80)
  - Chaapel's Seeds, 1919 (Box-folder 4 / 81)
  - Champlain View Gardens, 1957 (Box-folder 4 / 82)
  - Childs (John Lewis), 1887; 1899; 1902; 1908 (Box-folder 4 / 83)
  - Childs (John Lewis), 1918; 1920; 1923; 1924 (Box-folder 4 / 84)
  - Clapper Co., undated (Box-folder 4 / 85)
  - Coe's (E. Frank) Excelsior Guano, 1886 (Box-folder 4 / 86)
  - Coe, Converse and Edwards Co., undated (Box-folder 4 / 87)
  - Conard and Jones Co., Conard and Pyle Co. - Star Roses; 1898; 1911; 1918; 1945 (Box-folder 4 / 88)
  - Condon Bros., 1934; 1940; 1945; 1947 (Box-folder 4 / 89)
  - Cordon Bleu Farms, 1976; 1977 (Box-folder 4 / 90)
  - Currie Bros., 1892 (Box-folder 4 / 91)
  - Dam (William) Seeds, 1984 (Box-folder 4 / 92)
  - Darling and Beahan, 1913; 1915 (Box-folder 4 / 93)
  - DeGroot, Inc., 1991 (Box-folder 4 / 94)
  - Denholm Seeds., undated (Box-folder 4 / 95)
  - Deposit Seed Co., 1925 (Box-folder 4 / 96)
  - Dibble's Farm Seed Facts, 1921 (Box-folder 5 / 97)
  - Dickinson (O.), Oregon Seed and Horticultural Gardens, 1877 (Box-folder 5 / 98)
  - Dingee and Conard Co., 1891; 1892; 1894/3; 1894/5; 1894/8; 1895; 1896/1; 1896/3; 1896/4; 1896/12; 1897; 1898; 1899/3; 1899/4; 1900/1 (Box-folder 5 / 99)
  - Dingee and Conard Co., 1900; 1901; 1908; 1910; 1918; 1923; 1928; 1929; 1935 (Box-folder 5 / 100)
  - Dobie's Seeds, 1974; 1975; 1976; 1977 (Box-folder 5 / 101)
  - Domoto (Toichi) Nursery, undated (Box-folder 5 / 102)
  - Dos Pueblos Orchid Co., undated (Box-folder 5 / 103)
  - Dreer's (Henry A.) Garden Book, 1928; 1929; 1930; 1931; 1938 (Box-folder 5 / 104)
  - Duncan (Russell) and Sons Co., 1954; 1955 (Box-folder 5 / 105)
  - Dutch Gardens, Inc., 1980; 1990 (Box-folder 5 / 106)
  - Eastern States Farmers' Exchange, 1938 (Box-folder 5 / 107)
  - Edmund (Fred) Roses, 1980-81; 1993-94 (Box-folder 5 / 108)
  - Elliot Nursery Company, 1936 (Box-folder 5 / 109)
  - Ellis Bros., 1899 (Box-folder 5 / 110)
  - Ellwanger and Barry, 1905 (Box-folder 5 / 111)
  - Emlong's Nurseries, 1945; 1946; 1948; 1953; 1956 (Box-folder 5 / 112)
  - Emmons and Co., 1934 (Box-folder 5 / 113)
  - Endangered Species, 1980 (Box-folder 5 / 114)
  - Environmental Seed Producers,Inc., 1984; 1988 (Box-folder 5 / 115)
  - Everitt (J.A.) and Co., 1887; 1897 (Box-folder 5 / 116)
  - Farm Bureau Services, 1963 (Box-folder 5 / 117)
  - Farmers Elevator Co. of Arthur, ND, 1934 (Box-folder 5 / 118)
  - Farmer Seed and Nursery Co., 1920; 1934; 1937; 1942; 1948; 1949; 1951; 1953; 1954 (Box-folder 5 / 119)
  - Farmer Seed and Nursery Co., 1955; 1957; 1958; 1959; 1960; 1961; 1962; 1963; 1981 (Box-folder 5 / 120)
  - Farquhar (R.and J.) Co., 1886; 1903; 1908; 1909 (Box-folder 5 / 121)
  - Farr (Bertrand H.), 1922; 1923 (Box-folder 5 / 122)
  - Faust (H.G.) and Co., 1890 (Box-folder 5 / 123)
  - Faxon (M.B.), 1902 (Box-folder 5 / 124)
  - Ferguson Seed Farms, 1942 (Box-folder 5 / 125)
  - Ferndale Gardens, 1976 (Box-folder 5 / 126)
  - Ferris (Earl) Nursery, 1967 (Box-folder 5 / 127)
  - Ferry (D.M.) and Co. - Seed Catalogue, Universal Almanac; Seed Annual; Bulbs and Seeds; 1877; 1877-78; 1899; 1900; 1910; 1922 (Box-folder 5 / 128)
  - Ferry Morse Seed Company, 1938 (Box-folder 6 / 129)
  - Field (Henry) Seed and Nursery Co. (also see Num. 376-oversize, below), 1908; 1909; 1924; 1925; 1943; 1945; 1952; 1990; 1991; 1992 (Box-folder 6 / 130)
  - Fiske (H.E.) Seed Co., 1907 (Box-folder 6 / 131)
  - Fitzgeralds's Nursery, 1949 (Box-folder 6 / 132)
  - Ford (Frank) and Son, 1891; 1917 (Box-folder 6 / 133)
  - Forrest's Seed Co., 1908; 1927 (Box-folder 6 / 134)
  - Galloway Bros. and Co., 1914; 1918; 1919 (Box-folder 6 / 135)
  - Germain's, 1933; 1934; 1948; 1949; 1951; 1953; 1956; 1957; 1958 (Box-folder 6 / 136)
  - Glen Brothers Inc., 1917 (Box-folder 6 / 137)
  - Golden Rule Dahlia Farm, 1947 (Box-folder 6 / 138)
  - Goldfarb Garden Dept., 1947 (Box-folder 6 / 139)
  - Good and Reese Co., 1895; 1897; 1903 (Box-folder 6 / 140)
  - Good Luck Gardens, 193; 1945 (Box-folder 6 / 141)
  - Gordinier (H.W.) and Sons Co., undated (Box-folder 6 / 142)
  - Green's Nursery Co., 1900; 1911 (Box-folder 6 / 143)
  - Greening Nurseries, undated (Box-folder 6 / 144)
  - Gregory (James J.H.) and Sons, 1897; 1931 (Box-folder 6 / 145)
  - Griswold (Thomas) and Co., 1918; 1922 (Box-folder 6 / 146)
  - Gurney Seed and Nursery Co., 1909; 1910; 1922; 1923; 1925 (Box-folder 6 / 147)
  - Gurney Seed and Nursery Co. (also see Num. 377-oversize, below), 1927; 1929; 1934; 1935; 1941; 1961; 1962; 1963 (Box-folder 6 / 148)
  - Haines (Charlotte M.), 1928; 1930; 1937 (Box-folder 6 / 149)
  - Hallock (V.H.) and Son, 1889 (Box-folder 6 / 150)
  - Hammond (Harry N.) Seed Co., 1902 (Box-folder 6 / 151)
  - Harris (Joseph) Company, Inc., 1901; 1930; 1955; 1957; 1963 (Box-folder 6 / 152)
  - Harrison's (J.G.) and Sons Nurseries, 1920; 1947 (Box-folder 6 / 153)
  - Hart (Charles C.) Seed Co., 1925 (Box-folder 6 / 154)
  - Haskell Implement and Seed Co., 1908 (Box-folder 6 / 155)
  - Hastings (H.G.) Seed Co., 1935 (Box-folder 6 / 156)
  - Havens Orchids, 1986 (Box-folder 6 / 157)
  - Henderson (Peter) and Co., 1893; 1898; 1899; 1906 1912; 1913 (Box-folder 6 / 158)
  - Henderson (Peter) and Co., 1916; 1927; 1935; 1943 (Box-folder 6 / 159)
  - Herbst Brothers Seedsmen, Co., 1981 (Box-folder 6 / 160)
  - Heritage Gardens (Henry Field's Heritage Gardens), 1989 (Box-folder 6 / 161)
  - Heritage Rose Garden, 1990 (Box-folder 6 / 162)
  - Hick's Nurseries, 1920 (Box-folder 6 / 163)
  - Hildenbrandt's Iris Garden, 1986 (Box-folder 6 / 164)
  - Hill (D.) Nursery Co., 1923; 1930; 1931 (Box-folder 6 / 165)
  - Hoag Seed Co., 1949 (Box-folder 6 / 166)
  - Holland Bulb Farms, 1994 (Box-folder 6 / 167)
  - Holsinger Bros. Nurseries, 1914 (Box-folder 6 / 168)
  - Home and Garden Tricks Nursery, 1954 (Box-folder 6 / 169)
  - Hovey and Co., 1876; 1894 (Box-folder 6 / 170)
  - Howard's (Paul J.) California Flowerland, 1948 (Box-folder 6 / 171)
  - Howard's of Hemet (California), 1957 (Box-folder 6 / 172)
  - Hunt's Perfection Seeds, 1931 (Box-folder 6 / 173)
  - Huntington's Catalogue, 1936 (Box-folder 6 / 174)
  - Hurst & Son, 1930; 1931 (Box-folder 6 / 174.1)
  - Insecticides, Fungicides, Fertilizers and Sundries, 1951-52 (Box-folder 6 / 175)
  - Inter-State Nurseries, 1935; 1936; 1938; 1939; 1947; 1948 (Box-folder 7 / 176)
  - Inter-State Nurseries, 1959; 1963; 1966-Fall; 1966-Spring; 1973; 1988; 1989; 1990 (Box-folder 7 / 177)
  - Isbell Seed Co., 1926; 1937 (Box-folder 7 / 178)
  - Jackson and Perkins Co., 1955; 1960-1961; 1961-1962; 1962-1963; 1963-1964; 1965-1966; 1975; 1980; 1985; 1986; 1987; 1991; 1992; 1994 (Box-folder 7 / 179)
  - Jacques Seed Co., 1945 (Box-folder 7 / 180)
  - Jessamine Gardens, 1900 (Box-folder 7 / 181)
  - Johnny's Selected Seeds, 1982 (Box-folder 7 / 182)
  - Johnson Water Gardens, 1932 (Box-folder 7 / 183)
  - Jung (J.W.) Seed Co., 1916; 1933; 1934; 1939; 1941; undated (Box-folder 7 / 184)
  - Kallman's Garden Nursery, 1940; 1951; 1955; 1956 (Box-folder 7 / 185)
  - Kellogg (R.M.) Company, 1920; 1923; 1924; 1935; 1947 (Box-folder 7 / 186)
  - Kelly Brothers Nurseries, 1924; 1947 (Box-folder 7 / 187)
  - Kelsey Nursery Service, 1947 (Box-folder 7 / 188)
  - Kendall and Whitney, 1919 (Box-folder 7 /189)
  - Kendel (A.C.) Seed Catalogue, 1906 (Box-folder 7 / 190)
  - Kimberly Gardens, 1990 (Box-folder 7 / 191)
  - Kjorlie (Oscar H.) Co., 1960; 1963 (Box-folder 7 / 192)
  - Knight and Bostwick, Nurserymen, undated (Box-folder 7 / 193)
  - Krider Nurseries Inc., 1945 (Box-folder 7 / 194)
  - Kunderd (A.E.), 1928 (Box-folder 7 / 195)
  - La Sumida Nursery, 1965 (Box-folder 7 / 196)
  - Lakeland Nursery Sales, 1973 (Box-folder 7 / 197)
  - Landreth's Seed Catalogue, 1903 (Box-folder 7 / 198)
  - Lippincott (Miss C.H.) Flower Seeds, 1895; 1940 (Box-folder 7 / 199)
  - Livingston Seed Co., 1920 (Box-folder 7 / 200)
  - Lloyd's Gardens, undated (Box-folder 7 / 201)
  - Lovett (J.T.) Co., 1897; 1906 (Box-folder 7 / 202)
  - Maloney Bros. Nursery Co., 1923; 1945; 1947 (Box-folder 7 / 203)
  - Maple City Nurseries, undated (Box-folder 7 / 204)
  - Marble Iris Gardens, undated (Box-folder 7 / 205)
  - Markland (M.), 1934 (Box-folder 7 / 206)
  - Maule (William Henry) Seed Co., 1923; 1927; 1930; 1940; 1942; 1947 (Box-folder 7 / 207)
  - May (L.L.) and Co., 1893; 1914 (Box-folder 7 / 208)
  - May Seed and Nursery Co., 1927; 1964 (Box-folder 7 / 209)
  - McAllister (F.E.), 1883 (Box-folder 7 / 210)
  - McClure and Zimmerman, 1986; 1990; 1991 (Box-folder 7 / 211)
  - McGregor Bros., 1892; 1900; 1901; 1921; 1929 (Box-folder 7 / 212)
  - Meehan (Thomas) and Sons, 1913 (Box-folder 7 / 213)
  - Melk (George J.) and Son, 1965 (Box-folder 7 / 214)
  - Mellen (George H.) Co., 1917; 1925 (Box-folder 7 / 215)
  - Mellinger's Garden Catalogue, 1991 (Box-folder 7 / 216)
  - Michael-Leonard Co., 1895 (Box-folder 7 / 217)
  - Michell's (Henry F.), 1947 (Box-folder 7 / 218)
  - Midwest Wildflowers, 1984 (Box-folder 7 / 219)
  - Milaeger's Garden, 1993 (Box-folder 7 / 220)
  - Mill's Seed House, 1902; 1903; 1911; 1912; 1913; 1914; 1928; 1931; 1937 (Box-folder 7 / 221)
  - Mitchell Nursery and Floral Co., 1915 (Box-folder 7 / 222)
  - Monrovia Nursery Co., 1977 (Box-folder 7 / 223)
  - Montgomery Ward, 1934; 1936; 1949; 1951; 1955; 1959; 1964; 1967 (Box-folder 8 / 224)
  - Moore Miniature Roses, 1987 (Box-folder 8 / 225)
  - Morris and Snow Seed Co., undated (Box-folder 8 / 226)
  - Morse (C.C.) and Co., 1918 (Box-folder 8 / 227)
  - Moses (Alfred L.), 1946-47 (Box-folder 8 / 228)
  - Murvon Seed Co., undated (Box-folder 8 / 229)
  - Musser Forests Inc., 1957 (Box-folder 8 / 230)
  - National Arbor Day Foundation, 1981 (Box-folder 8 / 231)
  - National Seedsman Annual (Associated Seedgrowers, Inc.), 1936 (Box-folder 8 / 232)
  - Native Seeds/SEARCH Harvest Catalogue, 1988; 1989; 1990; 1991; 1992 (Box-folder 8 / 233)
  - Naughton Farms, Inc., 1941; 1947 (Box-folder 8 / 234)
  - Neosho Nurseries Co., 1939 (Box-folder 8 / 235)
  - Niagara Sprayer and Chemical Division, 1946 (Box-folder 8 / 236)
  - Nichols Garden Nursery, 1985; 1986; 1987; 1988 (Box-folder 8 / 237)
  - Nichols Garden Nursery, 1989; 1990; 1991; 1992; 1993 (Box-folder 8 / 238)
  - Nor'East Miniature Roses, Inc., 1985 (Box-folder 8 / 239)
  - O'Neill (Joseph) and Sons, 1947 (Box-folder 8 / 240)
  - Oak Hill Nursery, 1930 (Box-folder 8 / 241)
  - Olds' (L.L.) Seed Company, 1916; 1934; 1940; 1951; 1973 (Box-folder 8 / 242)
  - Olsen (N.J.) Co., 1926 (Box-folder 8 / 243)
  - Oriental Plant Co., undated (Box-folder 8 / 244)
  - Ortho Division, Chevron Chemical Co., 1969; 1973; 1975; 1976; 1977; 1980; 1981 (Box-folder 8 / 245)
  - Owen (Richard) Nursery, 1989 (Box-folder 8 / 246)
  - Park (George W.) Seed Co., 1896; 1897; 1899; 1904; 1917; 1922; 1923/2; 1923/3; 1923/5; 1923/8; 1923/9; 1923/10; 1923/11; 1923/12 (Box-folder 8 / 247)
  - Park (George W.) Seed Co., 1924/1; 1924/3; 1924/5; 1924/8; 1924/11; 1925/4; 1925/6; 1925/7; 1935; 1936 (Box-folder 8 / 248)
  - Park (George W.) Seed Co., 1943; 1960; 1966; 1967; 1980 (Box-folder 8 / 249)
  - Park (George W.) Seed Co., 1981; 1982; 1983; 1986; 1987 (Box-folder 8 / 250)
  - Park (George W.) Seed Co., 1988; 1989 (Box-folder 8 / 251)
  - Park (George W.) Seed Co., 1990; 1991; 1992 (Box-folder 8 / 252)
  - Park Nurseries, Park Nurseries (Holm and Olson, Inc.); 1930; 1931 (Box-folder 8 / 253)
  - Peacock Dahlia Farms, 1930 (Box-folder 8 / 254)
  - Pearce (Rex D.), Seedsman, 1947; undated (Box-folder 8 / 255)
  - Peterson (George) Inc., 1924 (Box-folder 8 / 256)
  - Pfitzer, 1927 (Box-folder 8 / 257)
  - Philipp's (Henry) Seed and Implement Co., 1901 (Box-folder 8 / 258)
  - Plant Seed Co., 1889 (Box-folder 8 / 259)
  - Pleasant Valley Nurseries, 1900 (Box-folder 8 / 260)
  - Plants of the Southwest, 1986 (Box-folder 8 / 261)
  - Quality Dutch Bulbs, 1984; 1986; 1988 (Box-folder 8 / 262)
  - Randall (Alton E.,) Nurseryman, 1912 (Box-folder 8 / 263)
  - Rayner Bros., 1947 (Box-folder 8 / 264)
  - Reeser (Charles A.) (Innisfallen Greenhouses), 1885; 1886; 1887; 1888 (Box-folder 8 / 265)
  - Reilly Brothers Nurseries, 1913 (Box-folder 8 / 266)
  - Reuter's Seeds, 1949 (Box-folder 8 / 267)
  - Reynolds' Farms, 1947 (Box-folder 8 / 268)
  - Rice (Jerome B.) Seed Co., 1909 (Box-folder 8 / 269)
  - Rich's Tuberous-Rooted Begonias, 1947 (Box-folder 8 / 270)
  - Robson Seeds, 1947 (Box-folder 8 / 271)
  - Rocky Ford Canteloupes Seed, 1949 (Box-folder 8 / 272)
  - Rogers Nurseries, 1947 (Box-folder 8 / 273)
  - Rohrer (P.L.) and Brother, 1923 (Box-folder 8 / 274)
  - Rosedale Nurseries, 1947 (Box-folder 8 / 275)
  - Rosehill Farm Miniature Roses, 1985 (Box-folder 8 / 276)
  - Rose Hill Nursery-Planting and Care of Nursery Stock, undated (Box-folder 8 / 277)
  - Roseway Nurseries, 1985 (Box-folder 8 / 278)
  - Royal Gardens, 1983 (Box-folder 8 / 279)
  - Rupert (W.P.) and Sons, 1912 (Box-folder 8 / 280)
  - Russell Gardens, 1954 (Box-folder 8 / 281)
  - Rynveld (F.) and Sons, 1931 (Box-folder 8 / 282)
  - Sands Seeds, 1992 (Box-folder 9 / 283)
  - Salzer (John A.) Seed Co., 1886; 1894; 1896; 1904; 1907; 1910 (Box-folder 9 / 284)
  - Salzer (John A.) Seed Co., 1912; 1914; 1917; 1918; 1919 (Box-folder 9 / 285)
  - Salzer (John A.) Seed Co., 1923; 1933; 1937; 1939; 1947 (Box-folder 9 / 286)
  - Santa Maria Bulb Gardens, 1931; 1932; 1933; 1934; 1935; 1936; 1937 (Box-folder 9 / 287)
  - Saxton's, 1956 (Box-folder 9 / 288)
  - Scarff (W.N.) and Sons, 1928 (Box-folder 9 / 289)
  - Schell's Quality Seeds (Walter S. Schell, Inc.), 1930; 1931 (Box-folder 9 / 290)
  - Scherer (S.) and Sons, undated (Box-folder 9 / 291)
  - Schlegel and Fottler Co., 1909 (Box-folder 9 / 292)
  - Schling (Max) Seedsman Inc., 1929; 1945; 1947 (Box-folder 9 / 293)
  - Schmidt and Botley, 1899 (Box-folder 9 / 294)
  - Schreiner's Gardens, 1954; 1982; 1986 (Box-folder 9 / 295)
  - Schultz's Seed Store, 1914 (Box-folder 9 / 296)
  - Scott (O.M.) and Sons Co., 1974; 1975; 1976; 1978; 1979 (Box-folder 9 / 297)
  - Seed Trade Buyers Guide and Directory, 1931; 1932; 1933; 1934 (Box-folder 9 / 298)
  - Seed Trade Buyers Guide and Directory, 1935; 1936; 1937 (Box-folder 9 / 299)
  - Seed Trade Buyers Guide and Directory, 1938; 1939 (Box-folder 9 / 300)
  - Seed Trade Buyers Guide and Directory, 1940 (Box-folder 9 / 300.1)
  - Self-Sufficient Seeds, 1983 (Box-folder 9 / 301)
  - Shepherd (Theodosia B.) Co., 1912; 1914 (Box-folder 9 / 302)
  - Shepherd's Garden Seeds, 1989 (Box-folder 9 / 303)
  - Sherman Nursery Co., undated (Box-folder 9 / 304)
  - Shivers (J.H.) Plant Farms, 1947 (Box-folder 9 / 305)
  - Smirnow (Lois), 1951 (Box-folder 9 / 306)
  - Smith (Howard) Rose Growers-Nurserymen, 1950; 1951 (Box-folder 9 / 307)
  - Southern Calif. Acclimatizing Assoc., 1911 (Box-folder 9 / 308)
  - Southern Nursery and Landscape Co., undated (Box-folder 9 / 309)
  - Southern Seedsman, 1950 (Box-folder 9 / 310)
  - South Michigan Nursery, 1937 (Box-folder 9 / 311)
  - Springfield Seed Co., 1907 (Box-folder 9 / 312)
  - Spring Hill Nurseries, 1947; 1956; 1965; 1969; 1976; 1988; 1991 (Box-folder 9 / 313)
  - Stahelin's Nursery, 1936; 1953; 1954; 1956 (Box-folder 9 / 314)
  - Stark Brothers Nurseries, 1934; 1939; 1947; 1974; 1986; 1987; 1988 (Box-folder 9 / 315)
  - Stark Brothers Nurseries, 1989; 1990 (Box-folder 9 / 316)